Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabroni, Florence, July 5, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Sismondi, J[ean] C[harles] Léonard] Simonde de, 1773-1852.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathizes with him over the loss of his post. Comments on his own exile.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 9x7-1/2; Smith, P[ierce
    Naples, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Has been ill. Hopes Signora Fabroni is better. Current events. Expects to leave the Mediterranean shortly.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Smith, Pierce
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes to live at his house, but if Fabroni cannot agree, wishes he would locate a house for him.
  - Letter to Signora Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 9x7-1/2; Smith, Pierce,
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning experiments on inflammable substances.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 27, 1807; B F113; 10x8; Société d'Agriculture du départment de la Seine.
    Paris, L.S.: Silvestre. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of a new colony for the advancement of agriculture.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 9, 1792; B F113; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London.
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.W.Wright. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers) Thanks for manuscripts pertaining to Americus Vespucius, presented by Sir J. Banks, Bart.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Oct. 30, 1779; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Solander, [Daniel Charles], 1736-1782.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes him success on his travels and forwards stones from Labrador.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Jan. 14, 1782; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Soldani, Ambrogio, 1733-1808.
    Siena, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Fontana.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Aug. 18, 1803; B F113; 11-1/2x8-1/4; Soldani, Ambrogio, 1733-1808.
    Siena, Printed L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications of the Accademia delle scienze.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb., 1802; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Starke, Mariana
    Exmouth, Devon, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for all of the kindnesses which he showed them when they were in Italy. Introduces two young friends.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabbroni [sic], Pisa, Dec. 31, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7; T[argioni-]Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1755-1829.
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Soldino. Scientific matters
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 1, 1799; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Talleyrand[-Perigord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Benevento], 1754-1838.
    12 Floreal an 7 L. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards two letters.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Oct. 21, 1790; B F113; 9-1/4 7-1/4; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1755-1829.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning coal.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], May 11, 1791; B F113; 8-1/2x7-1/4; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning coal.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], April 4, 1793; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Jan. 17, 1794; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Business matters for "milady."
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Paris, Jan. 7, 1799; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Mushrooms.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], May 7, 1802; B F113; 7-1/2x7-1/4; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards letter.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabbroni [sic], Pisa, Jan. 5, 1802; B F113; 9-1/2 x7-1/4; Targioni-Tozzetti, Ottaviano, 1759-1829.
    Florence, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Mineralogy.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 6-1/4x4-1/4; Tarnowski, Valérie
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Must return home, so cannot visit.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 3, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Tarnowski, Vladislas
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his visit to Rome. Met Humboldt.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, May, 1788; B F113; 8-1/2x7; Tessier, Abbé [Alexandre Henri], 1741-1837
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Will help him in his agricultural work as much as he can.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 24, 1789; B F113; 8x6; Tessier, Abbé [Alexandre Henri], 1741-1837.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his book on agriculture.
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabbroni,Florence, July 11, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arséne, 1777-1850.
    Livorno, Messidor 22, An 12 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Enjoyed visiting him. Asks about a rare bird. Refers to Potoki. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, Nov. 19, 1801; B F113; 11-1/2x8-1/2; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Refers to finding of the Rosetta stone. Egyptology.
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabbroni,Florence, Sept. 16, 1802; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Rome, 29 Fructidor an X A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Ceracchi and his works which were left, when he went to America.
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabbroni,Florence, Oct. 15, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Rome, 21 Brumaire an 11 A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommends Giuseppe Chiassi. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabbroni,Florence, Dec. 28, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is leaving Rome for Florence and asks him to take care of his luggage. Will visit him in Florence.
  - Letter to Giov[anni] Fabbroni,Florence, Jan. 9, 1803; B F113; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) His luggage. Has arrived in Florence and will see them.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, March 1, 1809; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Congratulates him on his honors. Asks that a friend be promoted to a teaching post.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, March 18, 1809; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning medicine.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, June 16, 1809; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Thiebaut[-de-Berneaud], Arsène, 1777-1850.
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian and French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning theories of the formation of iron crystals found in Elba.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 6, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thomas,
    Florence, L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Illness of a friend's wife. Trusts his discretion to forward a publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 12, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Thomas,
    L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks him again for his courtesies while in Florence. Thanks for teaching his son and giving him an interest in natural history. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni,Florence, June 11, 1788; B F113; 8x6-1/4; Thomas,
    L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning periodicals which are incomplete. Will soon go to Paris and will forward him anything he orders.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 3, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thomas,
    Paris, L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is to move from Paris. Concerning publications of various men. Asks if he is to continue publication on agricultural matters. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], B F113; 9x7-1/4; Thomas,
    Mardi matin [Tuesday]. L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Delighted that his son is better.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], B F113; 9x7-1/4; Thomas,
    Mardi, [Tuesday]. L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards letter. Sorry they have not seen each other in such a long time.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], B F113; 9x7-1/4; Thomas,
    Jeudi matin [Thursday morning]. L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot visit, due to illness of his son.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thomas,
    Samedi [Saturday]. L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Has shipped items to him already. Recalls their conversations with pleasure. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Signora Teresa Fabroni], B F113; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Thomas,
    Samedi [Saturday]. L.in 3rd.P. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks to borrow books.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 13, 1788; B F113; 7-1/4x6; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards seeds and speaks about his catalogue of plants which is to be published.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, March 28, 1789; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards seeds. Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 12, 1791; B F113; 8x6-1/4; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards seeds. Forwards prospectus of a news agricultural journal.
  - Letter to J[Giovanni] Fabbroni, July 30, 1797; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    12 Thermidore an 5 A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Raboul, who hopes to move to America.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Paris, March 5, [1799]; B F113; 4x6-1/2; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, 15 Ventose An 7 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Seal. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks him to give seeds to Pascal.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, March 1, 1812; B F113; 8x6; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Seeds are forwarded.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 15, 1815; B F113; 5x8; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    A.L.in 3rd.p. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends seeds.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 18, 1816; B F113; 5x8; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends seeds.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni,Florence, April 17, 1816; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Reports on plants developed from seeds from various areas.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 8, 1818; B F113; 4x5; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks him for gift of seeds.
  - Letter to Monsieur Favi, March 15, 1785; B F113; 4-1/4x6-1/2; Thouin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.,end. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks him to present seeds and list to Fabroni.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, March 7, 1787; B F113; 8x6-1/4; Thoüin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 7, 1787; B F113; 12-1/2x8; Thoüin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Plants.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 2, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Thoüin, [André], 1747-1824.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sent seeds by Favi: forwards additional seeds. Sends prospectus for prizes for agricultural betterment.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, B F113; 12x8-1/2; Throckmorton,
    Monday morning. A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards books and telescope. Will visit when he is better.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, April 13, 1791; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Thunberg, C[Karl] P[eter], 1743-1828.
    Upsala, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Has not received his diploma. Will send mineral specimens when shipping permits. Botanical specimens are being shipped to Fontana.
  - Manuscript leaf., B F113; 12-1/2x8-3/4; Tiraposchi, Gerolamo, Abbate, 1731-1794.
    A.D. 4p. Copy. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, Nov. 6, 1809; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Tobler & Figli
    Livorno, L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning coins.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 19, 1809; B F113; 7x4-3/4; Tochon [d'Annecy, Joseph Francois], 1772-1820.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Fabroni papers.) Invites him to dinner.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Paris, Feb. 7, 1810; B F113; 7x4-1/2; Tochon [d'Annecy, Joseph Francois], 1772-1820.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to J[ean] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 12, 1810; B F113; 10x8; Tochon [d'Annecy, Joseph François], 1772-1820.
    Paris, L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of an award for his work on numismatics. Concerning the medals and coins.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 29, 1814; B F113; 8-3/4x7-1/2; Tochon [d'Annecy, Joseph François], 1772-1820.
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Fabroni papers.) Has been ill and could not write. Comments on recent happenings. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, May 15, 1801; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Torlonia, Marino
    Rome, L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning writings. Refers to Lord Bristol.
  - Letter to Giovanni [Fabroni], Aug. 14, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Ulrici, Giovanni
    Poggio, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Ships barometer and thermometer.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Aug. 23, 1806; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Ulrici, Giovanni
    A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning meteorological readings.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 1, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Ulrici, Giovanni
    A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning meteorological observations.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Sept. 18, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Ulrici, Giovanni
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 1, 1806; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Ulrici, Giovanni
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Presents barometer.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 20, 1797; B F113; 8x7; Van Mons, J[ean] B[aptiste], 1766-1842.
    Brussels, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of his election and promises to send his diploma.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 23, 1798; B F113; 7x4; Van Mons, J[ean] B[aptiste], 1766-1842.
    2 Vendémiaire an 7 []. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Greets him on his appointment to the commission on weights and measures.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 17, 1798; B F113; 7x4; Van Mons, J[ean] B[aptiste], 1766-1842.
    Brussels, 27 Brumaire an 7. A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter concerning scientific works on geography, etc.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 5, 1803; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Van Swinden, J[an Henrik], 1746-1823.
    La Haÿe, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathizes with him over his loos, but assures him that all scientists recognize his worth. Thanks for gift.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Aug. 3, 1801; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Varges, [Edoardo, conte
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Degerando and Anisson.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 25, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Varges, [Edoardo, conte
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Dr. Meckel, German naturalist.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 22, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Varges, [Edoardo, conte
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Wants letters of introduction to men in northern Italy, where he goes to look for coal.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 28, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Varges, [Edoardo, conte
    Livorno, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is publishing a volume and wants an article from Fabroni. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 12, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Varges, [Edoardo, conte
    Livorno, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) His plans for travelling. Still wants an article for publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 10, 1808; B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Varges, [Edouardo, conte
    Pisa, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Is working on a publication on metallurgy.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, March 18, 1806; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassali-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a publication on metallurgy. Will pay postage when told how much.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, March 27, 1797; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Vassalli(?), M
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning various writers, including Hamilton in Naples, Macie [Smithson] and Priestley.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 11, 1802; B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antoine Marie], 1761-1825
    Turin, 20 Frimaire an 11 A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Study of medicine in Italy.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni,Florence, Sept. 24, 1807; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antoine Marie], 1761-1825
    Turin, L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Met his friends and wrote letters for them to Lyon.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, April 21, 1802; B F113; 8x5; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antoine Marie], 1761-1825.
    Turin, 1 Floreal an 10 []. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards his publication on weights and measures. Introduces two mineralogists
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, April 17, 1806; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning purchase of publications and forwards his publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 30, 1812; B F113; 11-1/2x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Jean Berruti and Mons. Grand.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 31, 1814; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces and recommends Anghilante.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 21, 1814; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Anghilante, the museum of natural history, etc.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 2, 1815; B F113; 10-1/2x8; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for the eloge on his wife. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 17, 1815; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Pisa, L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning various publications, including Deleuze and agricultural societies. Concerning scientific questions in Turin.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Dec. 18, 1806; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Vassalli-Eandi, [Antonio Mario], 1761-1825.
    Turin, L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Mr. Dueg, a German painter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, May 18, 1815; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Vassili-Eandi, [Antonio Maria], 1761-1825.
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Speaks of a person who wishes to study with him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 18, 1807; B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Vauquelin, [Louis Nicholas], 1763-1829.
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his knowledge and teaching of chemistry.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 7, [1801]; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Ventenat, [Etienne Pierre], 1757-1808.
    Paris, 19 Thermidor an 9. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for botanical specimens from Italy. Praises him and says all his friends remember him in Paris.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 6, 1816; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Venturi, [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Milan, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the institute.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 20, 1816; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Venturi, [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the institute.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 17, 1818; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Venturi, [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Reggio, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Presents copy of his work on geology.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 30, 1815; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Venturi, Giambatista [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Reggio, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers. ) Concerning his Memoira and its distribution.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 1, 1819; B F113; 10x7; Venturi, Giambatista [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Milano, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his work on Galileo.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 3, 1786; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Venturi, Giambattista [Giovanni Battista], 1746-1822.
    Modena, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning weights and measures.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], B F113; 9x7-1/4; W[ebster], E[lizabeth]
    Florence. A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter and asks for certain publications. Delivered his parcel to Sir Joseph Banks.
  - Letter to [Jean Hyacinthe de] Magellan, Aug. 26, 1778; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Walsh, [John?], 1725(?)-1795.
    Warfield, Berkshire, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him that Fabroni and Fontana will visit: the plants "will exert their Powers to entertain such Guests."
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 11, 1788; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Wedgwood, J[ohn], 1766-1844.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Quotes letter of his father concerning apparatus for Fontana. Quotes letter of Priestley on air.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 11, 1788; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Wedgwood, J[ohn], 1766-1844.
  - Letter to Sir Joseph Banks, London, Feb. 9, 1792; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Wedgwood, Tho[mas], 1730-1793.
    Etruria, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end.in Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning borers ready to be shipped. Chemistry. Refers to Josiah.
  - Letter to Signor Pelli, B F113; 7-1/4x5; Wicar, J[eanne] B[aptiste], 1762-1834.
    Florence. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Inquires about Fabroni.
  - Letter to John Davidson, New Castle-upon-Tyne, June 25, 1779; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Wilson, Andrew, 1718-1792.
    London, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Fabroni and asks that he be shown the coal mines.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, Dec. 18, 1775; B F113; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Woodford, T[homas]
    Leghorn, A.L.S. 2p.,add. (see Fabroni papers.) Regrets difficulties with Great Britain prevents his return the America. Refers to Mazzei.